Guide to the Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies records, 1966-2014 RL.11552
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Center Leadership and Administration, 1966-2014
  - Board of Governors (BOG), 1968-2014
    - Annual report materials, 1969-2012; 163 folders
      - Biographies M-W, Louis E. Martin Great American Award, 1969-2007; 5 folders (Box 24)
        Includes biographies of the Board of Governors and other leadership members used for the annual report, press releases, and external communications and is arranged alphabetically.
      - Annual report materials, 1970-2012; 54 folders (Box 20)
      - Strategic planning conferences and reports, 1971-2011; 11 folders (Box 22)
      - Biographies, A-L and unsorted, 1972-2007 (Box 23)
      - Program reports, 1978-1996; 39 folders (Box 21)
      - Financial reports, 1982-2007; 53 folders (Box 22)
      - Annual report materials, computer disk, 2004 (Box 19, Disk RL11552-OP-0147)
    - Audiovisual media, 1988-1990; 8 items
      This subseries contains audio cassettes of interviews/oral histories, dinner speeches, and meeting discussions, grouped by media.
      - Kenneth Clark tape, 1989 Jun 13 (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0007)
      - McGeorge Bundy tape, 1989 Jun 14 (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0008)
      - Director's retreat tape #1-#4, 1988 Jul 25; Jul 29 (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0009 - RL11552-CS-0011, RL11552-CS-0006)
      - Dinner program tape, 1993 Mar 30 (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0015)
      - 1990 Dinner program tape (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0016)
      - 1997 Annual dinner tape 1 (Box 172, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0151)
      - 1997 Annual dinner tape 2 (Box 172, Audio-cassette RL11552-CS-0152)
      - Joint Center dinner, #1, 2005 (Box 166, Video-cassette RL11552-Bcam-0016)
      - Joint Center dinner, master, #2, 2005 (Box 148, Videotape RL11552-Bcam-0012)
      - 2011 Annual dinner (Box 148, Videotape RL11552-DVCAM-0001)
  - Office of the President (OOP), 1968-2013
    This subseries is comprised of materials related to each Joint Center president's office: Eddie N. Williams, Togo D. West, and Ralph B. Everett. These files primarily consist of correspondence, speeches, and subject files. The subject files consist of correspondence and reports related to donors, such as the Ford Foundation and United Way, as well as documents concerning national policy changes and initiatives.
    - Eddie N. Williams (1972-2004), 1973-2004
      - Correspondence, mail and telephone logs, 1981-2003
        This subseries includes original incoming and copies of outgoing letters, memoranda and other correspondence with staff members and contacts outside of JCPES and is arranged chronologically.
        - Correspondence, 1981-1982; 25 folders (Box 29)
        - Correspondence, mail log, 1981-1985; 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 34)
        - Correspondence, 1984; 1986 Jan-Aug; 21 folders (Box 30)
        - Correspondence, 1986-1987; 17 folders (Box 31)
        - Correspondence, 1988; 13 folders (Box 32)
        - Telephone logs, 1989-1991; undated; 9 folders (Box 36)
        - Correspondence, 1989 Jan-Nov; 12 folders (Box 33)
        - Correspondence, mail log, 1990-1991 (Box 35)
        - Mail log, appointment books, 1981-1985; 1991 (Box 36)
        - Correspondence, 2000 Jun-2001 Dec; 21 folders (Box 37)
        - Correspondence, 2002 Jan-2003 Oct; 19 folders (Box 38)
      - Eddie N. Williams Subject Files, 1973-2004
        This subseries includes administrative materials, and audiovisual media, and is arranged chronologically.
      - Color of Money Show 712, Eddie N. Williams Guest Appearance, undated (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0041)
      - Eddie N. Williams, Ed Dorn - Black Caucus, undated (Box 149, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0017)
      - Eddie Williams - Tape 1, undated (Box 161, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0087)
      - Eddie N. Williams in Person with P. Berry, undated (Box 164, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0104)
      - Fox Morning news Segments with Eddy Williams and Rep. Louis Stokes, undated (Box 149, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0018)
      - Harrah's Entertainment, Board of Directors, ENW List, undated (Box 42)
      - JCC Holding Company Board of Directors, ENW List, undated (Box 42)
      - Correspondence, 1973 Oct 26 (Box 42)
      - Newspaper articles, 1979; 1984 (Box 42)
      - Speeches, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Civil Rights Two Decades Later, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
      - Rising to the Level of Self-Criticism, speech, 1985 Nov 2 (Box 42)
      - April press, 1988 (Box 42)
      - Eddie N. William's Appearance at the Strom Thurmond Institute, Clemson University, 1988 Mar 8 (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0032)
      - Eddie Williams on the Today Show: Minorities and the GOP, 1988 Aug 17 (Box 161, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0083)
      - Eddie N. Williams MacNeil - Center, 1990 Nov 9 (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0034)
      - MacNeil Lehrer with Eddie N. Williams, 1994; 1995 Mar 17 (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0036)
      - JCPES correspondence, 1995 Annual dinner, 1994; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Officers retreat, 1995 Sep (Box 42)
      - Correspondence, 1996-2003; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Eddie Williams, 1997 Sept 14 (Box 161, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0101)
      - Employees handbook, 1998 (Box 42)
      - Employee desk reference, 1998 Jun; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Eddie Williams on Washington Journal, 1998 Aug 13 (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0060)
      - Eddie N Williams on Washington Journal, 1998 Aug 13 (Box 161, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0093)
      - Employee Handbook, revised, 1998 Oct 22 (Box 42)
      - Riggs National Corporation of Directors, list, 1999 (Box 42)
      - Eddie Williams on Washington JRL Eighth National Policy Institute, 2000 Jan 20 (Box 161, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0070)
      - Luncheon meeting transcript, 2000 May 2 (Box 42)
      - Black Leadership Forum, 2000 Aug 18 (Box 42)
      - Eddie N. Williams retirement, 2002 (Box 42)
      - Eddie N. Williams on Politics C-SPAN, 2004 Aug 12 (Box 160, Video-cassette RL11552-VHS-0042)
      - Audio interview with Eddie Williams on Talk of the Nation (NPR), 2004 Nov 29 (Box 19, Disk RL11552-OP-0001)
      - Eddie N. Williams tribute, 2004 Dec 1 (Box 42)
    - Togo West, Jr. (2004-2006), 2005; 4 folders
      This subseries includes a statement on Eleanore Farrar's death, and an administrative briefing book, and is arranged chronologically.
      - Farrar Death, 2005 Aug 29 (Box 42)
      - Ford Foundation briefing book, 2007 Jan 10; 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Ralph Everett, Esq. (2007-2013)
      This subseries includes administrative materials and is arranged chronologically.
      - Presidential vision memorandum, 2007 May 8 (Box 42)
      - People's Inaugural Project event guests lists, invitations, planning, 2008-2009; 6 folders (Box 42)
      - Presentation templates, 2011-2012 (Box 42)
      - National Policy Alliance Biennial conference, 2012 Mar 29-Apr 1; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Minority Health conference, 2013 Feb 21 (Box 42)
    - OOP Subject files, 1968-2013
      This subseries includes files relating to meetings, events, programming, research, and administrative materials from each of the Joint Center presidents and is arranged alphabetically.
      - A Decade of Black Political Progress, 1967-1977, 1978 Mar 9 (Box 43)
      - A Policy Agenda for the Next Generation, undated (Box 43)
      - A Vision of the Future, undated (Box 43)
      - Ad Council, 1980 Apr-Aug (Box 43)
      - Adolescent reproductive health, 2003 (Box 182)
      - Affirmative Action: A Course for the Future, 1996 Aug (Box 43)
      - Affordable Care Act of 2010: Creating Job Opportunities for Racially and Ethnically Diverse Populations, 2013 Oct (Box 43)
      - Alexander & Alexander, 1982 Sep 1 (Box 43)
      - American Can Company, 1986 Mar-Jun (Box 43)
      - Analysis of the Black Vote in the November 4 Elections, 1980 Nov 7 (Box 43)
      - At the Center, 1991 Jun (Box 43)
      - Bailout cases, 1981 (Box 52)
      - BEOs, 1981 (Box 52)
      - Bill of Rights, 1991 Jan-May (Box 43)
      - Black Aged, 1985 May 16 (Box 43)
      - Black Campaign retreat, 2007 Feb 24 (Box 54)
      - Black Federal Executives, 1978 May-Dec (Box 43)
      - Black initiatives and government responsibility, 1987 (Box 52)
      - Black Leadership Forum, 2007-2010; 8 folders (Box 54)
      - Black Mayors Congressional Summit, 2009 Mar 17 (Box 54)
      - Blacks in Government, 1979-1982 (Box 43)
      - Blackout: A Strategy for Black Self-Determination in the '80s, 1981 May-Jun (Box 43)
      - Briefing memorandum, 2012 Oct 2 (Box 43)
      - Briefing research funders, 1991-1996 (Box 85)
        Includes: Aetna, Ameritech, Arco, Donnelly & Sons, Eli Lilly, Honeywell, James Irvine Foundation, ICI Americas, Joyce, Henry J. Kaiser Foundation, William and Flora Hewlett Foundation
      - Briefing research President's Club, 1991-1996 (Box 85)
      - Britton, John H., draft for JCPS annual report, 1981 Aug 27 (Box 43)
      - Broadband Opportunity summit, 2009 Feb 25 (Box 43)
      - Gladys Brooks Foundation, 1985 Apr-Jul (Box 43)
      - Budget Stabilization and Leadership, 2003-2005; 2 folders (Box 85)
        Includes: Kellogg Foundation, American Express, Ford Foundation, General Motors, Joyce Foundation, Knight Foundation
      - C&P Executive Loan Program, 1983 May 23 (Box 43)
      - Carnegie Council correspondence, 1986-1991; 7 folders (Box 52)
      - Census, 1979-1982 (Box 52)
      - Centennial Celebration, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 43)
      - Chicago Assembly, 1982-1984 (Box 43)
      - Cine, 1990 (Box 43)
      - CNN Poll, undated (Box 43)
      - Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 43)
      - Coleman Young v. Philip Klutznick, 1980 Sep 25 (Box 52)
      - Corporate Associates follow up meetings, 1982 Sep 23 (Box 43)
      - Committee on Racial Justice, 1987 Jan (Box 43)
      - Committee on Racial Justice correspondence, 1985-1989; 6 folders (Box 52)
      - Community Problem Solving Task Force, 1986-1987 (Box 43)
      - Communication/publications memoranda, 1981-1992; 4 folders (Box 53)
      - Communication workshops, undated (Box 43)
      - Conference on the Status of Blacks in Urban America, 1980 Sep 22 (Box 43)
      - Congressional Black Caucus, 2006-2009 (Box 43)
      - Congressional committees, undated (Box 52)
      - Copyright Office - Library of Congress, 2001 (Box 2)
      - Corporate correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 43)
      - Corporation for Enterprise Development, 1980 Dec-1981 Feb (Box 43)
      - Congressional Black Caucus, 1981-1986 (Box 43)
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 43)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, 1985-1991 (Box 43)
      - Council on Foundations membership list, 1984 Apr (Box 43)
      - Daedalus, 1980 Mar-May (Box 43)
      - DC Municipal Research Bureau, 1977 Jun-1978 Jul (Box 43)
      - Democratic National Convention, 2008 (Box 54)
      - Democratic National Policy, 1985 Jun-Jul (Box 43)
      - Dinner programs, 1978; 1981 (Box 43)
      - Documentary proposals, 1989-1990 (Box 44)
      - Du Centenaire de la Découverte du Nouveau Mande, 1990 Nov 28 (Box 44)
      - EEOC Seminar, 1980 Spring (Box 44)
      - Rodney Ellis, 1989 Apr 28 (Box 44)
      - Emerging Issues Policy Forum conference, 2008 Oct 12-14 (Box 54)
      - Energy and Environment program, 2011-2013; 2 folders (Box 85)
        Includes: Walmart, Kresge, Entergy, Hewlett Foundation, UMass, General Motors, Ford Foundation
      - Energy and Environment program, transition, 2012-2013; 2 folders (Box 85)
        Includes: Kresge, Climate Action Campaign, NMQF/Kapor-Online Power Plant Mapping, A-A Leadership Clean Cars event, Jobs Proposal 1, Green Jobs Analysis, Entergy, SEIA-Solar Energy Jobs Study
      - Everett correspondence, 2008 (Box 53)
      - Field Foundation, 1982 Mar; Jun; 1984 Feb (Box 44)
      - FOCUS interview, Dr. Alfred Balitzer, 1981 Mar 27; Dec 10 (Box 44)
      - FOCUS survey questionnaire, undated (Box 44)
      - Ford Foundation, 1985-1988; 3 folders (Box 44)
      - Ford Foundation correspondence, 1978-1989; 7 folders (Box 53)
      - Ford refunding, 1989 (Box 44)
      - Ford Foundation final report, 1991 May (Box 44)
      - Fourth National Policy Institute, 1983-1984; 4 folders (Box 44)
      - Foundation Center, 1985-1989; 7 folders (Box 44)
      - Friday meetings, Lawyers Committee on Civil Rights, 1981 (Box 52)
      - Funding the Black Agenda, 1981 Sep 25 (Box 44)
      - Greensboro interview, Susan Glission, 2007 Jun 27 (Box 44)
      - Gibbs, Jewelle Taylor, 1992 Jul 1 (Box 44)
      - Haley, 1985 (Box 44)
      - Harold Hodkinson, 1985-1986 (Box 44)
      - Hazen Foundation, 1985-1986 (Box 44)
      - Hewlett Foundation, 1981-1987 (Box 44)
      - HBO Lists, 1983 (Box 45)
      - HBO Screening list, 1994 (Box 45)
      - Henderson, Lenneal, 1980-1982 (Box 45)
      - Holden, Matthew, 1989 Sep 1 (Box 45)
      - Homeboys film, 1989 Sep 28; 1990 Jan 16 (Box 45)
      - Housing vouchers, 1981 (Box 45)
      - Hunton & Williams legal fees, correspondence, 2002-2004 (Box 45)
      - Hunton & Williams legal invoices, 2002 (Box 45)
      - Hydroelectric Power, 1983-1984 (Box 45)
      - Impact of Sequestration on Communities of Color, 2013 Feb 28 (Box 54)
      - Important Questions, Informed Answers, 2008 Sep 22 (Box 85)
      - Independent Sector annual conference, 2007-2010; 5 folders (Box 54)
      - In Memphis: Mirror to America, 1986 Apr 28 (Box 45)
      - International Affairs, 1985-1986 (Box 53)
      - International Club, 1986-1988 (Box 45)
      - JCPES Capabilities, 1994 Jul 13 (Box 85)
      - JCPS and Children Defense Fund pre-conference meeting, 1985 Feb 27 (Box 45)
      - Johnson Foundation, 1981-1986; 1988; 3 folders (Box 45)
      - Joint Center Forum, Congresswoman Fudge, 2013 May 8 (Box 54)
      - Joint Center open house, 2012 Oct 2 (Box 54)
      - Joyce Foundation, correspondence, 1982-1987; 3 folders (Box 45)
      - Kellogg Foundation, America Healing Anchor Organization Convening, 2011 Aug 19; 4 folders (Box 54)
      - Kettering Foundation correspondence, 1985 (Box 53)
      - Kilson, Martin, 1985 (Box 45)
      - King March on Washington, 1982 (Box 45)
      - King Holiday Bill, 1979 (Box 45)
      - King Week, 1982 Jan 13 (Box 45)
      - MacArthur International, 1990 Jan (Box 45)
      - Lane, Ambrose, I. - An Alternative Plan for Economic Recovery, 1981 Feb-Mar (Box 45)
      - Lawsuit exhibits, 2002 Jul 17 (Box 45)
      - Lawsuit - JCPES vs. Minority Business roundtable, 2002-2004; 4 folders (Box 45)
      - Lawsuit materials, 2002 (Box 45)
      - Lawsuit pleadings binder, 1A-1B, 2002; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Lawsuit pleadings binder, 1C-1D, 2002; 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Lawsuit transcript of motions hearing, 2002 Aug 23 (Box 45)
      - Leadership in Energy and Climate Policy, 2009 Feb 14 (Box 54)
      - League of Women Voters, 1987-1989 (Box 46)
      - Ike Leggett, 1986 Mar 13 (Box 46)
      - Links Forum, No Child Left Behind, 2007 Feb 27; 3 folders (Box 54)
      - Eunice Lockhart-Moss, 1981-1984 (Box 46)
      - Loury, Glenn, 1984-1985 (Box 46)
      - Llewellyn Institute, 2000 Feb 9 (Box 46)
      - MADD, 1984-1985 (Box 46)
      - Martin Luther King, Jr., Realizing the Dream, 2009 (Box 54)
      - Marketing director search, 1985-1985 (Box 53)
      - Master list, 1987 (Box 46)
      - Mays, Benjamin E., 1980; 1988 (Box 46)
      - Maxima board meeting, 1990 Aug 22; 3 folders (Box 46)
      - Maxima Corporation, correspondence, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 46)
      - Metropolitan Life Foundation, 1985 (Box 46)
      - Meeting planning - retreats, committees, annual, 2001-2012; 20 folders (Box 28)
      - Microsoft TechFest conference, 2009 (Box 54)
      - Millennium Group, 1984 (Box 46)
      - Ministry business development, 1982 (Box 46)
      - Minority Enterprise, 1980 (Box 46)
      - Minority Executive Placement Program, 1979 (Box 46)
      - Minority Media & Telecom Council, 2008-2009 (Box 54)
      - Morgan Management Systems, undated (Box 46)
      - Charles Stewart Mott Foundation, 1986 (Box 46)
      - Nabre grant, 2002-2003 (Box 46)
      - The Nation, article, undated (Box 46)
      - National Advisory Committee on Federalism, 1984 Nov 27; 1985-1986; undated; 4 folders (Box 46)
      - National Bar Association magazine, 1991 Apr (Box 46)
      - National Black Agenda, 1979-1980; 3 folders (Box 46)
      - National Black Economic Summit, 1982 Apr-Jul (Box 47)
      - National Black Education Summit, 1983 Dec 16-22 (Box 47)
      - National Black Leadership roundtable, 1980-1987 (Box 47)
      - National Black Republican Council, 1978-1982 (Box 47)
      - National Black Agenda, 1980-1981 (Box 47)
      - National Caucus of Black School Board Members, 1985 Jun 10 (Box 47)
      - National Coalition on Black Voter Participation, 1986 May (Box 47)
      - National Coalition on Black Voter Participation, correspondence, 1989 (Box 53)
      - National Conference of Black Mayors, 2008 Jun 4-8 (Box 54)
      - National Elections seminar, 1980 Nov 20 (Box 47)
      - National Endowment for Democracy, 1990 (Box 53)
      - National Endowment for Democracy, correspondence, 1987-1989; 3 folders (Box 47)
      - National Football League, racial discrimination, 1980-1982 (Box 47)
      - National Organization of Black County Officials conference, 2007 May 17-20 (Box 54)
      - National Organization of Black University and College Students, 1981 (Box 47)
      - National Political Congress of Black Women, 1984-1985 (Box 47)
      - NIE Adult Illiteracy, 1985-1985 (Box 47)
      - NTL Institute, 1984 Nov 10-16 (Box 47)
      - National Roster of Black Elected Officials, 1969 (Box 47)
      - National Youth Pilgrimage, 1980 May 17 (Box 47)
      - News releases, news clips, 1981-1984; 3 folders (Box 47)
      - New World Foundation, 1984-1986 (Box 47)
      - Notes from Milton Morris, 1981 (Box 52)
      - Notes from Dan Weiss, 1981 (Box 52)
      - Office of Finance and Administration financial reports and budget proposals, 1986-1990; 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Office of Public Affairs, 1990 (Box 53)
      - Orphanages, 1995 (Box 47)
      - Overseas Development Council, 1988-1989; 5 folders (Box 47)
      - Patent and trademark certificate of registration, 2003 Feb (Box 24)
      - People's Inaugural Project event, guest list, 2009 Jan (Box 54)
      - Personnel case studies, 1982; undated (Box 47)
      - Pharmaceutical research and manufacturers, 2008-2009 (Box 54)
      - Polyarchy and Participation - Terchek, Ronald J., undated (Box 52)
      - Post-election luncheon, 2012 Nov 7 (Box 54)
      - Potomac Electric Power Company, 1994; 2000 (Box 181)
      - Presidential activity, 2012 (Box 47)
      - Presidential Debate watch event, 2012 Oct 3 (Box 54)
      - President's Breakfast Series, Thomas J. Donohue, 2013 Mar 12 (Box 54)
      - President's Breakfast Series, Rev. Al Sharpton, 2013 Jun 4 (Box 54)
      - President's Breakfast Series, Janet Murguia, 2013 Oct 22 (Box 54)
      - President's Commission on Housing, 1981 (Box 47)
      - Proposals, studies, 1979-1981 (Box 47)
      - Proposed Master Plan for the Centennial Celebration, 1986 (Box 47)
      - Public Good, 1989 (Box 47)
      - Public policy television, 1990 (Box 47)
      - Raising the Minimum Wage, 2007 Jan (Box 48)
      - Rape culture research, 1991 (Box 48)
      - Referrals, undated (Box 48)
      - Reidentification - Sumter County, Alabama, 1981 (Box 52)
      - Reidentification - Wilcox County, Alabama, 1960; 1978; 1980 (Box 52)
      - Rejections, undated (Box 48)
      - Report of the Comptroller of U.S. - VRA -- Enforcement Needs Strength, 1976-1980 (Box 52)
      - Research, 1981-1992; 5 folders (Box 53)
      - Rising African American Leaders: Challenges for a New Generation, 2006 (Box 48)
      - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1983 (Box 48)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, correspondence, 1978-1987 (Box 53)
      - Scholars Clearinghouse, 1986 (Box 48)
      - Scholars Clearinghouse, appendix A, undated (Box 48)
      - Scholars Clearinghouse, contact information, undated; 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Scholars Clearinghouse, mailing list, 1986 Jul 29 (Box 48)
      - Scholars Clearinghouse, vita, 1986; undated (Box 48)
      - Senior Staff meeting, notes, 1981-1989; 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Separate and Unequal Education, 1989 (Box 48)
      - Sloan Foundation, 1986 (Box 48)
      - South Africa, 1984-1985; 1990; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Southern Education Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 48)
      - State and Local Leadership Project, 1981 (Box 48)
      - Stern Foundation, 1982 (Box 48)
      - Strategic planning correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 85)
      - Taconic Foundation, 1989 (Box 48)
      - Tampa Organization of Black Affairs, 1982 Jan 14-15 (Box 48)
      - Teleconferencing, 1981-1985 (Box 48)
      - Trademark certificates, 2003 (Box 2)
      - Wallace Terry Foundation, 1979-1982 (Box 48)
      - Clarence Thomas research, 1991 (Box 48)
      - United Way of America, 1987-1990; 31 folders (Box 48, Box 49, Box 50)
        includes correspondence and programming.
      - Vice President correspondence, 1986-1992 (Box 53)
      - Vice President - Eleanor Farrar, Denise Dugas Office of the President, 2000-2002 (Box 42)
      - Voices of the Electorate, 1992 (Box 50)
      - Voting rights extension, 1975 (Box 52)
      - WETA Television, 1990-1991; 4 folders (Box 50)
      - What Lies Ahead, 1989 (Box 50)
      - Williams, Eddie, 1985 May-Jul (Box 50)
      - Xavier University Advisory Committee on the Institute for Social, Economic, and Political Studies, 1989 (Box 50)
      - YMCA of Metropolitan Washington, 1981-1983; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Contractors and employees, 1970-2010; 27 folders
      This subseries includes Distinguished Scholars Program applications, contracts, agreements, position descriptions, work plans, reports, and documents related to the hiring process and is arranged chronologically. Information concerning specific full-time and part-time positions, as well as those hired to carry out certain projects, can be found here.
      - Contractors and employees, 1970-2010; 27 folders (Box 180)
- Center Offices, 1969-2013
  The Center Office series is divided into four subseries: Office of Development and Strategic Planning (ODSP) with materials consisting of prospective and major donor correspondence and reports that date from the early 1970s to 2011; Office of Governance and Economic Analysis (OGEA) which is comprised of the Joint Center reports from major research and policy initiatives sponsored by the Center; Office of Information Resources (OOR) consists of print materials published by the Joint Center, as well as reference sources used for research purposes; and Office of Communication and Marketing (OCM) which consists of published materials, organizational information, newsletters, magazines, employee profiles and resumes, documentary film proposals and transcripts, and electronic media.
  - Office of Governance and Economic Analysis (OGEA), 1969-2008
    This subseries consists of early writings, reports, and studies. The early writings relate to surveys and studies, funding initiatives, quarterly reports, and management training information. Reports and papers comprise the largest part of the series and pertain to various research and funding initiatives sponsored by the Joint Center. Topics include demographics, housing, employment, voting, leadership, education, and health. Various reports related to specific projects or entities, such as the National Policy Institute, can be found here.
    - OGEA Papers, 1970-1988
      This subseries contains event, policy, program, and project proposal papers. These materials did not have a discernible original order and have been arranged chronologically by topic.